

□+34634491616 | ≥ sebastian.daza@gmail.com | ★ sdaza.com | □ sdaza | □ sdaza

# **Summary**\_

I am a senior data scientist and analyst with practical experience designing, managing, supervising, and analyzing applied industry and social studies. I possess strong quantitative and qualitative skills, as well as a background in health, social, and behavioral sciences. I am excited to apply my knowledge and skills to research and influence people, and I enjoy working with interdisciplinary and multicultural teams.

# Work Experience \_\_\_\_\_

**Teladoc (Telemedicine)** 

SENIOR DATA SCIENTIST Apr 2023 - Present

- Technical lead in data science, personalization, and causal inference (internal workshops and technical guidance)
- · Led uplift modeling and incrementality testing of media campaigns with geo-experiments and A/B tests
- Created experiment and causal inference package for imbalance adjustment (IPW, IV), meta-analysis, and power analysis
- Developed a multi-touch attribution (MTA) model to evaluate investments in paid media and optimize spending
- Developed a life time value (LTV) model that helps inform marketing investments for optimal results
- · Create LLM pipeline with Azure OpenAI to extract information from doctors' notes and content generation
- Created tools to process data efficiently with PySpark and Databricks (e.g., internal Python packages, CICD pipelines, Terraform)
- Automated the generation of metrics using PySpark
- Created Tableau dashboards that provide insights to stakeholders

### **Lookiero (Online Personal Styling Service)**

Remote, Spain

Jun 2022 - Feb 2023

SENIOR DATA SCIENTIST

- Technical lead in data science and causal inference (internal workshops and technical guidance)
- Used statistical models to identify sources of product success (variance decomposition)
- Causal estimation of discount strategies. Simulation of scenarios. Increased the contribution margin more than 5%
- Developed a hybrid recommendation model using more than 200M feedbacks from users
- · Contributed to define a framework to iterate neural network models in Databricks (PySpark), decreasing time in training

#### Institute of Economy, Geography and Demography, CCSH-CSIC

Madrid, Spain

SENIOR DATA RESEARCHER ANALYST

Dec 2019 - Apr 2022

- · Led a team of researchers to study early conditions, delayed adult effects and morbidity, disability, and mortality
- Led Scrum ceremonies and tracked progress using Notion
- Authorship of 5+ academic papers and presentations in conferences
- · Supervised and implemented complex data analysis on demography and genomics using R and Java
- Health modeling and simulation using Anylogic

## Juntos Global (Conversational technology platform for financial users)

May 2018 - Dec 2019

DATA SCIENTIST

• Led analytic and data science team for banking user insights

- Provided user insights through the design and analysis of experiments (A/B testing), improving banks' engagement
- · Implemented NLP and machine learning models to classify banking users and topics and help to resolve their needs
- · Worked closely with Product Managers, Software Engineers, and Design team to improve Juntos' banking engagement product
- Collaborated in the design and implementation of the data pipeline using Python, PySpark, and Databricks

#### Center for Studies in Demography and Ecology, UW-Madison

Madison, US

RESEARCH ASSISTANT

Jul 2014 - May 2018

- · Communicated insights to different audiences in 5+ empirical research papers, and 10+ presentations at scientific conferences
- Led all aspects of 5+ research studies (funding, design, analysis, reporting)

#### **Center for Social Studies, Catholic University**

RESEARCH DIRECTOR

May 2005 - Jul 2010

- · Led several research projects in areas such as organizational studies (engagement surveys and culture analysis), political perception and government approval ratings, education (curriculum impact), tobacco and substance, and crime and delinquency
- A key project was the Survey of Social Cohesion in Latin America(ECosociaL) that involved 7 countries: Chile, Argentina, Brazil, Colombia, Guatemala, Mexico and Peru, and 10,000 cases

NOVEMBER 28, 2024 SEBASTIAN DAZA · RÉSUMÉ 1 **Consulting** 

Kreuger Consulting, LLC Texas, U.

DATA SCIENTIST May. 2021 - Jul. 2021

- Created an interactive data dashboard tool using R and Shiny, to visualize the output of a Covid-19 agent-based model
- Provided domain stakeholders with the ability to interact with and modify the results displayed

**Personio** Madrid, Spain

 DATA SCIENTIST
 May. 2020 - Jul. 2020

- · Created an interactive data dashboard tool using R and Shiny to assess recruitment performance and transition rates between interview states.
- · The dashboard also simulates hiring scenarios to estimate the number of interviews and recruiters needed by position, role, and office.
- It improved the detection of bottlenecks and assessment of performance.

#### **Applied Population Lab, UW-Madison**

Madison, US

Oct. 2016 - Jul. 2018

- Created R package to extract variables and statistics from the American Community Survey and Decennial US Census.
- The package automatized the extraction of data and improved the time for reporting.

### **Center for Social Studies, Catholic University**

Santiago, Chile

Jul. 2010 - May. 2018

- Designed samples and post-adjustments in large studies (organizational, public opinion, and educational studies)
- Provided methodological guidance (attrition, non-response adjustment)

# Skills

DATA SCIENTIST

DATA SCIENTIST

**Programming** Python, R, Java

Data science ML, NLP, DL (Keras), Visualization (Dash, Shiny), PySpark, Petastorm, SQL, Redshift, PostgreSQL, Databricks

Stats/modeling Causal inference, AB testing, hierarchical modeling, survival analysis, Bayesian statistics, simulation, agent-based modeling (ABM)

**Survey design** Sample design, weighting, non-response adjustments, bias analysis, technical reporting, methodological evaluation

**Tools** Notion, Trello, Jira, Confluence, Git, Latex

**Languages** English, Spanish

**Teaching** Prepared course materials on statistics and modeling, and wrote feedback for 200+ students.

# **Software**

**experiment-utils** Python package for analysis and design of experiments

acsr R package to extract variables and statistics from the American Community Survey and Decennial US Census

**zotnote** Python package to extract notes from Zotero (Reference Manager)

# **Education**

### **University of Wisconsin-Madison**

Madison, US

PHD IN DEMOGRAPHY AND SOCIOLOGY

The Data Incubator Washington DC, US

DATA SCIENCE PROGRAM

## **Catholic University of Chile**

Santiago Chile

MASTER OF ARTS IN SOCIOLOGY

November 28, 2024 Sebastian Daza · Résumé 2